on today's video we are going to make
sugarfree habiscus
[Music]
sbet yeah this one's pretty simple
there's um not a lot going into this one
we are obviously we've got dried
habiscus
youve never seen these they're kind of
like a Ry purple kind of
color um we're going to
use xylol because it's easily accessible
in lots of places around the world we're
going to do it in the Ninja creamy cuz
this recipe was requested by someone on
patreon and only other thing we're going
to need is
inulin and a stabilizer of some kind I'm
going to use G gum because there's no
need to heat this right up to 85 CRA so
let's get everything that we need to
make habiscus
SB you're going to need a pan some
scales this is going to make a 1.5 L
batch so that's two ninja creamy deluxe
three St standard ninja creamies or a
big old 1 and 1/2 lit batch for your
standard ice cream machine we're going
to start with water we're going to need
1,114 G of water into that we're going
to steep our dried habiscus but before
we do that what we're going to do is
we're going to put our xylol in and our
inul in and just warm that up a little
bit just to make sure that they're
completely dissolved so into our water
we're going to add 240 G of Xyloto for
those that aren't aware SB has a sugar
content or sugar substitute content of
anywhere between 25 and
35% that is essential for a couple of
reasons one because of the solids that
are going in with there and two to
create the texture without that amount
of sugar in the texture becomes super
dry and powdery and you can't avoid that
I see online like you know in Facebook's
ninja creamy groups and stuff people
suggesting some of the most weird ways
of just softening up just just make it
properly then you won't have any issues
stop teaching people hacks just make it
properly balancing a recipe is super
important and it's even more important
in ninja creamies as well because you
can't eat the whole tub or you shouldn't
be eating the whole tub in one go you
know unless it's something like a a zero
sugar high protein and you're doing that
for your diet just learn to balance the
recipes properly I'll do a video on how
to do that in the next few weeks so you
can actually see how easy it actually is
in yourin 144 G we are using inulin to
boost the solids because without this
we're going to be really really low on
solids and that basically means that
you're just churning water that is our
SB mix there let's get this warming up
gently just going to take a whisk turn
this on and get this warming up cuz what
we're looking to do is just dissolve the
xylol and the inulin powder in our water
so I'll come back once that's done
shouldn't take any more than 5 minutes
minutes right turn the heat off we don't
need this on here anymore and what
you'll find is the whiteness of the
powder has dissipated is become
semi-opaque and it's opaque because
we've added solids to this water all
right we've got the solids from the
xylol and the solids from the inulin
they've now completely dissolved the
last thing to do is to take our dried
habiscus 3 tablespoons and stir those in
because we're now going to leave this
for an hour just sitting here doing
nothing getting that habiscus taste and
color into our mixture ready so I'll
come back once we're ready to move on
right we've been sleeping for an hour we
got a couple of things to do first one
is we've got 5 G of xyl here which is
just one teaspoon and we're going to
take our gag gum which is 2 G here our
stats for this are as follows a minus 15
C serving temperature obviously zero
sugar
25.4% % solid which is a tiny bit low
74% water which was which is a tiny bit
High pod of 169 and a pack of 368 so the
pack 368 is cuz it's got a-7 temperature
so with our G gum in there like that
we're just going to mix that together
add that into there mix that up there's
some residual warmth left here enough to
dissolve that xylol so we're just just
going to stir that for 10 15 seconds gum
has dissolved our xyl dissolved we've
steeped that we're now going to pour
pull this through a fine mesh saeve we
have a glorious color here really really
nice color and all we're going to do is
is fill up our ninja creamy
tubs get those in the freezer
overnight and we'll come back and spin
it next day let's get this one spun up
wonderfully smooth flat top if you guys
wonder why you get the bump on top then
let me know in the comments and I'll do
a short video on it it's pretty
straightforward but it does mean you'll
need to change how you make your ice
cream so let's get this
sbet
spunner
[Music]
SB hibiscus sbet dried hibiscus flowers
super easy to make very floral kind of
smell which you'd
expect oh that's
delicious Ultra smooth ninja creamy is
kind of like the go-to for sbet if you
make a lot of sbet you want to make a
lot of SB just just buy ninja creamy
don't bother buying anything else that
is so good the texture is perfect
consistency is perfect super easy to
spin no ninja creamy bump on top this
recipe is perfect a beautiful sbay give
this one a try got these on Amazon not
going to do an affiliate link head over
them or just buy them from wherever you
can hope you enjoyed this nice easy
delicious ninja creamy habiscus sawway
thanks for much for watching don't
forget to like And subscribe for more
Ninja creamy recipes and I'll see you
next week
[Music]